Vyom Khanna, Data, BI & MI Analyst

Southampton, UK | +447733989297 | vyomkhanna355@gmail.com | Linkedin | Portfolio

PERSONAL PROFILE:

3 years of experience in Data Analysis, Business Intelligence, and MI Reporting, with an MSc in Data and Decision Analytics. Proficient in SQL, Python, Power BI DAX, Tableau, Qlik, and Excel for data extraction, transformation, visualisation and tailored reporting. Capable of managing time, communicating clearly, and quickly adapting to new challenges with a willingness to learn.

EDUCATION:

University of Southampton | Southampton, UK | Sep 2023 – Sep 2024

Masters of Science – Mathematics - Data and Decision Analytics (Provisional 65%)

- Conducted Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) using Python libraries and established a predictive model; optimising bike-sharing resources and leading to an estimated 20% improvement in bike availability.
- Developed 20+ Power BI visualisations that analysed sales trends by region and product for 3 years, leading to an estimated 15% increase in retail sales.
- Optimised a SQL database for hospital staff shift allocation, designing queries to analyse schedules and work hours, resulting in an estimated 25% reduction in conflicts.

See More

Key Modules: Data Analytics, Data Science Techniques of Python, Snowflake, Statistical Computing for Data Science, Machine Learning, SQL, Power BI Data Visualisations, and Deterministic Methods for Data Science

SRM Institue of Science and Technology | Chennai, India | Jul 2016 – Dec 2020 Bachelor of Technology – Mechanical Engineering

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Business Intelligence Developer / Analyst | Team Computers Pvt Ltd, Gurgaon, India | Sep 2021 - May 2023

- Utilised SQL and Python for healthcare insurance client data analysis, presenting KPIs and insights.
- Developed and maintained Power BI and Oliksense dashboards and provided ad-hoc decision-making support.
- Automated 100+ reports in Python and Qlik, reducing manual efforts.
- Optimised SQL, DAX queries, and Qlik ETL models, increasing data accuracy to 95%.
- Increased online policy sales by 20% and improved sales productivity by 15%.

See More

Graduate Engineering Trainee | Nipa International, Gurgaon, India | Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

- Improved Siemens appliance efficiency by 20% via supply chain and design optimisations.
- Drove supplier negotiations, reducing procurement costs by 18% based on data-driven insights.
- Increased production efficiency by 15% by using Power BI and Excel for targeted process improvements.

See More

Commercial Data Analyst Intern | IP Infra, Delhi, India | Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

- Developed weekly and monthly Tableau dashboards for metrics like sales performance, customer acquisition, and churn, providing senior management with actionable insights.
- Improved pricing strategy by accurately forecasting sales trends with SQL and Excel analysis.

See More

SKILLS:

- Data Analytics: Python and SQL
- Data Visualisation: Power BI (DAX), Tableau, QlikSense, QlikView
- Excel: Pivot tables, VLOOKUP, MATCH, IF/What-If analysis, Power Query and Microsoft Office (PPT, Access, Word)
- Statistical Modelling: Linear Regression, Random Forest, XGBoost, Decision Tree
- Soft Skills: Analytical Thinking, Stakeholder Communication, Problem-Solving, Time Management

CERTIFICATES:

- Microsoft Power BI for business intelligence and data analytics
- SQL and Python Bootcamp for data analytics

References available upon request